Adebayo Tolu Majaro

Software Developer

Contact

Address

Ottawa, ON K2A 1Z1

Phone

613-809-7352

E-mail

tolumaj@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/majaro-adebayo/

www

https://github.com /maja0011

Skills

Java

React.is

Node.is

C++

C#

MongoDB

Python

Linux

MySQL

Scrum & Agile

Recent software developer graduate with 2 years of professional experience in web and software projects. Seeking a web or software developer role. My demonstrated ability of being hands-on, adaptable, and well organized, combined with my continued interest in learning new technologies, are why I would be a great fit for your job opening.

Work History

2021-09 -Current

Banquet Server

Westin, Ottawa, ON

- Collaborate with colleagues to ensure successful events and customer satisfaction during events.
- Train and supervise new employees, ensuring they maintain attention to detail during events.
- Responsible for the preparation and execution of events based on customer needs.

2021-09 -2022-04

Software Developer

Pivot & Edge, Ottawa, ON

- Supervised and lead a team of developers during the development of a robust upgraded version of the company's software application, resulting in improved user experience and an extra feature for the application.
- Implemented new features using React.js, including adding a button that extracts information from the database and changes the format into a more user friendly format.
- Integrated the company's job posting application with Microsoft Teams to allow communication of data between both platforms.
- Used Agile methodologies for the process of the software development cycles, from bi-weekly sprints to weekly stand-ups with teammates.

2021-05 -2021-09

Information Technology Technician (Co-op)

Smart Living Properties, Ottawa, ON

 Built and configured computer workstations for both onboarding employees and existing employees, occasionally adding or removing computer accessories as required.

Methodologies

- Provided networking and desktop support for clients.
- Focused on providing client service, over the phone and in person, including: network support, desktop support, and workstation configuration.
- Configured file share systems for various departments so employees could see real time changes in their documents.
- Maintained the office network systems including:
 Wifi, Firewall, camera networks and network switches.
- Prioritized daily tasks using a ticket system to keep work orders organized.

2021-01 -2021-05

Technical Analyst (Co-op)

MNP Technology Solutions, Ottawa, ON

- Created web templates using Adobe Experience
 Manager (AEM) software to allow clients to publish
 articles within a shared online workspace.
- Compiled Java EE and JavaScript packages using Maven and other webpack tools when building AEM projects.
- Worked with the GIT tool for version control of the code base.
- Participated in daily scrum meetings to discuss the status of tasks to be completed within the project, including their prioritization, completion timelines, and any roadblocks.

Education

2018-09 -2022-06

Computer Engineering Technology Diploma

Algonquin College - Ottawa, ON

• Dean's List [February 2022]